Jewish War Veterans Collection 0009.001.003a
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
Jewish War Veterans
1896-2012
0009.001.003a
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
4.5 Cubic feet 4.5 cubic feet of documents and photographs plus 3 cubic feet of artifacts
Biographical/Historical note
The Jewish War Veterans of the United States (JWV) is the second oldest veterans' organization in the country. It was founded by Civil War veterans in 1896 as the "Hebrew Union Veterans" to fight the perception that Jews had failed to shoulder their duty on either side of the Civil War.
A second group of Jewish veterans, formed as a result of the Spanish American War, eventually merged with the first group, and subsequent wars provided new members. The organization's name changed in 1920 to Jewish Veterans of the Wars of the Republic and changed again sometime within the following decade to Jewish War Veterans of the United States.
Concern for the perception of Jewish veterans as "slackers" led to various programs to combat anti-Semitism in general. Programs were instituted to promote inter faith relations, patriotism among school children, and "Americanization."
Not only did the organization exist to counter negative perceptions of Jews, but it also provided many service programs. According to an anniversary history published by the JWV, it led a world wide boycott movement against Hitler's government beginning in 1933. During WWII, the JWV developed a plan to aid the war effort through bond sales, donations to the government for the purchase of fighter planes, ambulances, and other equipment, and blood drives. The JWV opened canteens, provided recreational programs for soldiers, and matched veterans with soldiers to provide them with correspondence and comfort packages. The Ladies' Auxiliaries provided visitation and recreation programs for hospitalized soldiers. Rehabilitation programs for veterans were expanded to meet the needs of returning WWII soldiers. These services were often provided without regard for soldiers' religious affiliations.
The Hartford Post #45 of the JWV was founded in 1931 or 1933. It was active locally in all of the programs listed above, including visitation of veterans at the hospital in Newington, sponsorship of a fund drive for a fighter plane, and work as an advocate for families of deceased veterans after the war.
Post #45also provided several officers for the national organization, including Milton Richman who became National Commander in 1947. In 1946, Laurel Post #394 was formed, but the two merged in 1953 as the Hartford Laurel Post #45. The Post #45 Auxiliary and two posts in New Britain, Harry Berson Post #56 and Eddy Glover Post #6 are also documented in the collection.
In addition to the JWV, this collection contains other military and WWII era material. A large portion of this documents the provision of social activities for soldiers and veterans by the local Army/Navy Committee of the Hartford Jewish Community Council and the Army/Navy Committee of the United Service Organization/Jewish War Board (USO/JWB).
The collection also contains the information gathered during the Jewish Women in WWII project that was done in conjunction with the Women's Archive in Boston, MA, this is a growing collection – starting in November 2008.
The Veterans History Project series, done in conjunction with the Library of Congress, began in 2011 as an effort to collect oral histories from veterans. This collection contains CDs of the oral histories, as well as supporting documentation for each one.
War; War Veterans
- Series I: Individuals
  - Individuals/A-K, undated
  - Individuals/L-Z, undated
  - Individuals/Baer, Seymour, undated
  - Individuals/Barall, Stanley M., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Beck, Louis, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Bedick, Aaron, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Berkowetz, Herman S., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Block, Hyman C., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Bloom, Leonard I., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Blum, Jerome (Jerry) D, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Brody, Joseph, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Bruskin, Sydney, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Budin, Milton, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Carlson, Carl, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Cheerman, Aaron, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Cohen, Benjamin, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Cohen, Louis, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Coleman, Saul R., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Cooper, Benjamin, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Cooper, Hyman, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Cooper, Miriam, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Diamond, Harry, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Donn, Elliot, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Eisenberg, Richard S., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Epstein, George, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Esakov, Daniel A., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Feinberg, Julius, Scrapbook, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Filkoff, Jacob G., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Galin, Julius L., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Gelb, Armin, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Gerber, Harry M., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Gittleman, Arthur, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Goldberg, Benjamin Bernard, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Goldfarb, Harold L., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Goldfield, Jerome "Jerry", undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Goldman, Robert, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Goldstein, Arnold, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Goldstein, Benjamin, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Hollm, Bennie, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Homar, Abraham, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Horenstein, Herman, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Horwitz, Mel, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Jacobson, Jacob R., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Kargman, Lawrence M., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Karp, Saul A., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Kaufman, Leo, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Kaufman, George and Ida, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Kaufman, Stanley, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Kimenker, Robert M., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Kohn, Harold, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Kovalsky, Joseph, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Lapidus, Robert Jacob see Businesses/Clothing/Bob's Stores Inc., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Lebovitz, Jacob M., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Levine, Israel, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Levitow, John Lee, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Lustig, Irv, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Manekofsky, Irving, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Michaelson, Elliott, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Miller, Henrietta, "Chickie", undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Miller, Jay M., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Morrison, Abraham, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Pahuskin, Lester J., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Pessin, Lewis and Harold, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Postman, Benjamin, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Rakow, Jerome "Jerry", undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Reich, Albert, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Reiter, Gilbert, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Richman, Milton, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Richmond, Henry, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Richter, Samuel, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Rose, Maury, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Rosenberg, Milton, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Rosenbilt, Jack, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Rosenblatt, Emil H., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Sandik, Sidney, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Sarota, Irving, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Schoen, Gilbert, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Schuman, Burt, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Schwartz, Milton, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Shaker, Theodore, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Shauer, Ken, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Shapiro, Benjamin, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Shear, Manuel, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Shear, Nathan, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Shechtman, Leonard, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Sherrow, Monroe, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Sholovitz, Herman, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Slusky, Harold D., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Smith, Harold, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Sowalsky, Meyer S., undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Spiegelman, Irving, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Stein, Bernard G, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Stein, Milton, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Tierney, Jim, See People and Oral History, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Title, Samuel, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Weil, Gershon, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Weiner, Joseph, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Wolinsky, Isadore, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45, undated (Box 1)
  - Individuals/Boardman, Sol, 1942-2012; Newspaper obituary, Military History Record, Honorable Discharge Papers
    Biographical/Historical note
    Mr. Boardman received the Good Conduct medal and the Purple Heart. He was stationed in New Guinea during the war.
    Boardman, Sol; Jewish War Veterans; World War II
- Series II: Hartford Laurel Post, A-M
  Hartford Laurel Post #45; Jewish War Veterans; Vanguard, The
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Anniversaries/100th, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Anniversaries/60th, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Anniversaries/15th Anniversary of the Post, 1948, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Anniversaries/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Annual Reports, 1940s, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Association of the US Army-CT Chapter, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Auxiliary/Meeting Programs, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Auxiliary/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Auxiliary/Newsletter, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Auxiliary/Service Programs, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Awards, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/CT Veterans Day Parade/Certification of Participation/2004-, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Band, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Board of Directors/Members, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Board of Directors/Minutes, 1938 1940, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Community Service Projects/"What Memorial Day means to Me," 2000s, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Cemetary Maintenance, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Founding 1934, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Hartford Laurel Post #394/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Historical Highlights, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Holocaust memorials, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Interfaith Activities/Citizens Award, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Iraq forces, 2004, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Meeting Programs, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Members and Membership, undated (Box 2)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
- Series III: Hartford Laurel Post, N-Z
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 1947-1982 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 2000-2002 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 2003-2005 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 2006-2010 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newsletter, "The Vanguard," 2011-, 2011-2012 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newpaper Clippings, 1930's-1960's, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newpaper Clippings, 1970's-1980's, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newpaper Clippings, 1990's, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Newpaper Clippings, 2000-, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Photographs (copies), undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Remembering WWII, 1996, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Roster 1958-1959, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/September 11 commemorations, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Service Programs, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Soldier Support Program, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Veterans' Day Parade/Sabbath, 2002 and 2004, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45/Veteran's Home, undated (Box 3)
- Series IV: Department of Connecticut
  - Department of Connecticut Auxiliary/Annual Reports, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Connecticut/Board of Directors/Members, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Connecticut/Conferences/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Connecticut/Conferences/12th Annual Convention, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Department of Connecticut/Memorial Highway Designation, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Department of Connecticut/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Connecticut/Photographs (copies), undated (Box 4)
- Series V: Jewish War Veterans (General) A-Z
  - Jewish War Veterans/Avon Old Farms Convalescent Home/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Civil War, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Connecticut Veterans Hall of Fame, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Historical Highlights, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Jewish Soldiers' and Sailors' Welfare Committee/Miscellaneous (1917) (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/National Jewish Welfare Board/A Book of Jewish Thoughts, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/National Museum of American Jewish Military History, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/National Organization/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/National Organization/Miscellaneous and Holocaust Related Material, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/New Britain Eddy Glover Post #6/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/New Britain Sgt. Harry Berson Post #56/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Newington Veterans' Hospital, 1940's, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Sherman Museum Exhibit, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Oral History 1993 (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Other Organizations Providing Veterans' Services/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Pamphlets, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/Prayer Books, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/U.S.O.-J.W.B. Army-Navy Committee/Army Navy Construction Award/A.I. Savin Construction, 1943, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/U.S.O. J.W.B. Army-Navy Committee/Financial Information/Acct. Journal, 1943 45 and U.S.O. J.W.B. Army-Navy Committee/Financial Information/Check Register, 1944 51 See JWV Scrapbook box, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/U.S.O. J.W.B. Army-Navy Committee/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/U.S.O. J.W.B. Army-Navy Committee/Photographs (copies), undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/U.S.O. J.W.B. Army-Navy Committee/Photographs (copies), undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/U.S.O. J.W.B. Army-Navy Committee/Photographs (copies), undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/U.S. War Department/Army-Navy Construction Award/A.I. Savin Construction, 1943, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/West Hartford Veterans' Memorial, 2000s, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/World War II Miscellaneous Information, undated (Box 5)
  - Jewish War Veterans/WTIC, 1917-2012 (Box 5)
- Series VI: Oral History Series/Women in Service
  - JWV Honors Female Vets, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Apter, Ethel, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Basch, Diane Cohen, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Brody, Sarah Ragovin, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Bronstein, Norma Goldschmidt, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Greene, Juliette Novik, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Konover, Doris, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Lieberman, Irma, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Mileikowsky, Alice Marder, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Miller, Henrietta, "Chickie", undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Novarr, Sylvia Greenbaum, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Seltzer, Shirley Cohen, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Susman, Lynn, undated (Box 6)
  - Women/Wolinsky, Rebecca Strough, undated (Box 6)
- Series VII: Jewish Women in World War Two Project
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Exhibit/2009 (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Exhibit/Artifact Descriptions, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Release Forms, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Adler, Libby, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Allweiss, Helga, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Allweiss, Netti, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Aptor, Ethel, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Basch, Diane Cohen, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Berman, Charlotte, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Borstein, Viola Elizabeth Gerry, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Brody, Sarah Ragovin, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Bronner, Leah, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Bronstein, Norma Goldschmidt, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Cooper, Miriam, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Engelman, Muriel Phillips, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Feldman, Ida Freedman, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Field, Jane, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Goldstein, Gladys, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Gordon, Eunice, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Gordon, Sylvia, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Greene, Julie Novarr, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Gross, Cynthia, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Gundersheimer, Lenore, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Holden, Renee, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Kagen, Marcia Pessin, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Katz, Rosalyn Natalie, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Konover, Doris Marcus, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Lappen, Phyllis, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Lowengard, Elaine Title, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Mileikowsky, Alice Marder, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Miller, Henrietta Ann, undated (Box 7)
- Series VIII: Jewish Women in World War Two Project
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Rafal, Marjorie, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Rome, Helga, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Seltzer, Shirley, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Spector, Leah, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Spungin, Estelle, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Stamm, Molly, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Weil, Jean, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Wolfberg, Libby, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Oral Histories/Wolinsky, Rebecca Strouch, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project /Photos/Jewish Welfare Board, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Photos/Kagen, Marcia, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project /Photos/Muriel Engelman's Scanned Photos, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Pride, Honor & Courage (film)/DVDs of film, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Pride, Honor & Courage (film)/Notes, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Pride, Honor & Courage (film)/premiere, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project/Pride, Honor & Courage (film)/publicity, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project /Road show/ Publicity, undated (Box 8)
  - Jewish Women in WWII Project /Road show/DVDs of Scanned Images, undated (Box 8)
  - Veterans History Project, undated (Box 8)
  - Veterans History Project/Gabens, Seymour, undated (Box 8)
- Series IX: Scrapbooks
  - Hartford Laurel Post #45 Auxiliary scrapbook, 1958 1964 see JWV scrapbook box Statewide JWV scrapbook, 1940s see JWV scrapbook box The Julius Feinberg scrapbook containing information on the New Britain JWV chapters is located in the folder under his name in "Individuals' Military Service. (Box Oversized)
- Photographs: Miscellaneous/Groups
  - Jewish War Veterans of the United States:, undated (Box 1)
  - Connecticut National Guard/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - Dept. of Connecticut/Conferences, undated (Box 1)
  - Dept. of Connecticut/Memorial Highway Designation, undated (Box 1)
  - Events/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Post #45/Band, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Post #45/Fundraising/Fighter Plane, WWII, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Post #45/Interfaith Activities/Citizens Award. See also OVERSIZE drawer, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Post #45/Memorial Day Activities, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Post #45/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Post #45/Roster of Service Men and Women, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Post #45 Auxiliary, undated (Box 1)
  - Honor Roll dedication, Blue Hills WWII Veterans, near firehouse, undated (Box 1)
  - New Britain Eddy Glover Post #6, undated (Box 1)
  - New Britain Eddy Glover Post #6 Auxiliary, undated (Box 1)
  - Services/Guam/1945, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified Auxiliary, undated (Box 1)
  - Civil War/5 Civil War Veterans (composite), undated (Box 1)
  - Civil War/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - World War II/Newington Veterans' Hospital/Rolling bandages, undated (Box 1)
  - World War II/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980s, undated (Box 1)
  - Other Organizations (with Jewish Connections) Related to the Military:, undated (Box 1)
  - Avon Old Farms Convalescent Home, undated (Box 1)
  - Connecticut National Guard, undated (Box 1)
  - St. Francis Hospital Volunteer Aides, WWII, undated (Box 1)
  - U.S.O.?J.W.B. Army/Navy Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - U.S.O.?J.W.B. Army/Navy Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - U.S.O.?J.W.B. Army/Navy Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - U.S.O.?J.W.B. Army/Navy Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - U.S.O.?J.W.B. Army/Navy Committee/Seder and Shabbat at Emmanuel Synagogue, undated (Box 1)
  - Veterans' Administration, undated (Box 1)
- Photographs:Individuals
  - Individuals/Unidentified, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/[Maisl], Arnold, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Apter, herb, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Aron, Morris, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Baggish, Bennie, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Baumstein, Harold, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Bieber, Edward, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Blum, Howard S., undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Breslau, Sol, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Brody, Joseph, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Cantarow, Joseph, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Cohen, Aaron, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Cohen, Harry, Palestine, 1919, undated (Box 2)
  - Individual/Feltman, Phil, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Freund, Simon, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Ginsburg, Ida Gitten, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Gorbom, Harry A., undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Grabowky, Harold, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Greenbaum, Jack, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Homar, Abraham, undated (Box 2)
  - Individuals/Kendzur, Max S., undated (Box 2)